okay uh maybe I'm gonna start
the
um from the beginning so uh welcome to
uh the our course uh speech recognition
and the understanding
and uh today uh I will talk about the
overview of the course but properly
spend most of the time for the uh the uh
uh some of the uh the the logistics of
the lecture and so on and if I have some
more extra time I make uh dive into the
uh some of the contents a little bit but
today I remotely uh explain about
logistics
to this today's agenda so first uh the
uh we're gonna we will talk about the
instructor online resources basic format
and I think many people actually want to
know the grading policy right which I
did some of the information in response
to some of you but I will try to clarify
and the
uh this is the official operating policy
but of course some of them can be the
the changes depending on the situations
but uh I will spend some time for the
other grading policy textbook and the
other important part will be the
schedule
it is still tentative you know depending
on the situation we have to adjust our
schedule and so on but we will try to
give you the own kind of a schedule uh
today in this today's agenda and the
hope I can also have uh extra time to
introduce this course itself and the uh
the introduce I will try to introduce
myself yeah
okay so uh the first uh the uh
instructor and the TA
um um again I will have prepared some
kind of uh the same interactions right
uh but anyway uh for now uh I will uh
introduce uh there's some minimum
information I'm Shinji what another
Shinji call me Hindi that is fine and
the office is GHC 6.05 and I already
picked the uh the office number Tuesday
one to two pm
uh one hour and every week and the uh
please use this office server but the
previews that this uh spreadsheet uh and
they figure out your kind of uh the uh
the the
appointment in advance so that we will
not happen but uh that uh the conflict
uh with other people and if you know uh
the the usually the beginning uh the
actually the office hours are not very
busy and I want to use this time for my
kind of work and so on so it'll be great
to see you guys uh the use this
spreadsheet to put that uh the uh your
kind of appointment in other ones and I
apologize that my kind of a time is not
very flexible and I already fixed it to
Tuesday one to two PM but I we will try
to make the other pH uh the office hours
to be more flexible and I'll try to
cover everyone as much as possible so
data limit actually make a call and then
the uh try to find the best uh the pH uh
the office I want to cover everyone's uh
the the uh the the availability and
maybe it's good time to also introduce
HTA one other Shanghai
yeah my name is
okay and the next event hello
and the last uh
yeah thanks
so this time
usually you know we try to have a little
bit diverse okay but I intentionally uh
selected all my PhD students since I try
to kind of make this uh
uh texture to be a little bit more for
the uh this structured than the previous
one the previous ones were also good but
as you know deep learning a lot of kind
of advanced AI Technologies changing our
our area so we have to kind of update
our lifter
in some timing period and due to that I
kind of want to have my other student
help so assign that three of them to my
Tas and by the way as did maybe I can
also mention in The Piazza
umti and even is in ECE so if you guys
have you know specific some kind of
issues related to ECE uh that asked the
event and the the other FBI people uh
would also asked
and so on
okay cool and then the I kind of showed
you the beginning but I will explain
again and again since this is very
important so at the this question uh we
will yes I guess every year now using
Fiesta so I think I don't have to
explain you know the tool but some
teachers for example using the fiesta
campus or whatever and so on but in my
case is I own try not to use the mainly
kind of tools and I just put in the
piatta for the discussions and also
uploading the PDF and the videos and so
on
and they put a grading are the
assignments related we use the grade
scope and so on
so uh and that we also try to centralize
the information in the web page but it
is not updated often
so what I will do is I will try to
frequently upload the for example course
materials and so on uh in the theater
and even videos I am taking the video
now oh actually then I I don't have to
move so much wrong here
and the other uh the uh stuff that are
grading and so on again using the other
a greater scope and then all the
assignment materials will be putting the
uh the greatest call so after you guys
get the theater uh access please also
access to the other grade score again in
some cases uh if we use a camera
uh we could automatically import people
that registering this course and then we
can also export this information to the
previous call we could do it but this
time I don't use canvas at all so I will
not have a way to do this so instead of
asking you guys to register uh by
yourself okay
and the basic format of the course is
the like that
we of course have our lecture
uh which is mostly kind of technical
discussions because sometimes we also uh
discuss about the assignment uh the uh
to the other people uh to the students
since it is also important component
and the we will also hover uh the the
maintaining our toolkit espnet features
a very good uh famous uh Speech question
toolkit and we the mostly want you guys
to use these two uh for some uh the
project uh and so on of course you guys
can you know use your own tools or
whatever uh depending on your kind of
research problems and your kind of the
interest and so on uh but uh the uh the
espnet is easier for us to support your
activities
so that we are our kind of upgrading and
the important part uh some of you may
noticed uh these are the lectures
actually had a final
uh the final exam but we actually uh
decided not to have a final exam since
it is a super busy period of people
actually have to you know study the
final exam and the cost and product of
the center which I want to avoid
and another issue another issue another
point is that the uh the main actually
important concepts are explained in the
beginning
so uh that probably it's a good idea to
insert the midterm exam instead of the
final final exam so we put this midterm
exam in October 26th so Market to your
calendar
we also have a guest director
and the note that all of the activities
are in person supposed to be in person
and the again I am using Zoom but this
is only for the recording purpose and I
will not release this other Zoom link
and the people could not actually uh the
the
join this lecture are from the
okay next I will move to the grading
policy
so we have a four types of the uh the uh
the grading category one is the cross
participation which is actually required
to write a question 30 percent
and the second is assignments
uh features also about the same same
with the other big portion of 30 percent
and so we have a midterm exam 20 percent
and the term product 20 percent
and I will explain about each of the
items bit more details later
but before moving to the uh each of the
item I just want to have our General
comment about it because always this
hasn't actually these two
so first uh grading policy
I will already find about other set some
kind of point a clearly for each of
those assignment or each of the the
class participation points and so on and
you guys could for example get the the
final uh the point of the you know
90x or something like that but please
remember that this is the absolute score
and we will adjust this score to make it
for example on the
adjustments
[Music]
so for example you know everyone gets 70
then you know everybody I'm going to be
a kind of a other issue right which is
you know uh that we will definitely not
having such kind of situations everyone
is in the lower score we try to adjust
it and the same for the uh the the uh
the higher cases as well yeah we will
try to avoid it but which is very great
if everyone is you know over 99 which is
very cool to give you you know Air Force
as many as possible but if it's too many
maybe I need to adjust it uh please
understand it so this is the kind of the
most how they say uh the frequent claim
you know oh my God my calculation says
that my point is 95 so it should be a
plus please change it I'm not accept it
okay but of course you know if we eat it
you know the Euro College creation is
you know 95 but you know your score is
so on greatest here so definitely we
will consider but with some small
adjustment always happens so especially
you know a plus a boundary a A plus a
boundary uh a a minus boundary this is a
very kind of a subtle uh the adjustment
happens so uh the uh it's I'll say that
we may not mostly accept uh this grid
except that if we have a you know very
critical mistakes please of course ask
us but otherwise
oh you don't have that yeah again this
is the most the frequent uh question so
I just want to make sure that
oh another thing is a degrading request
we were happy to uh the the uh the
accept regulating if since you know we
are not perfect we will have our a lot
of mistakes during the grading right
especially uh when we kind of making a
point and so on
but uh
but in some cases some people for
example asking you know other all the
kind of their uh pay the point uh the
weeds are degrading uh the the uh the
request speech uh just kind of making
our workload to be very large so we
really want to avoid it so a priests are
the ah the the work on the
professionally yeah that's my kind of
request yeah of course definitely we
will accept degrading uh the request but
we should not make it every time and so
on yeah
um
okay so next I will move to the uh each
of the kind of uh the uh the point
first a cross participation
which are the we try to change from the
uh the previous lecture which you guys
may not know but anyway uh we will make
a class participation in the Importer
component and we will try to make it a
little bit uh interactive so that people
can also try to uh not to be born about
worrying about my lecture
so anyway uh how to kind of account the
participation
we will actually ask you guys a short
quiz
Dexter
and even in the theater
the BF why I really want you guys to
join the fiesta
and then we make a call
and then that we are collecting the uh
the European the world answer and then
dividing it
at least participate
okay
then there are
the people make pyramid oh I am
definitely worth in the cross but I just
you know didn't do that kind of work
uh
uh okay uh can you can can we get the
point I will say no because we don't
have a way to record it this is a way to
record your participation
and the we have a 22 regular courses the
definition of the regular courses means
that the excluding the ESPN is tutorial
and the term event
digital
courses
and the basically if you guys are the
the answer the quiz uh you guys get the
one point for each course
and you could authenticate the total 22
points and the additional two point some
VR uh the bonus or you guys can also use
these two points to kind of for example
skip the courses if that is helping your
kind of some of your products
and the Death Drive of this
uh the quiz is usually the end of the
class of course because we want to check
whether people are there during the
course and forum however depending on
the quiz for example it takes time and
so on we will definitely consider some
kind of buffer
uh that's uh depending on the other
short quiz uh the type and the schedule
uh and so on
and we also have a two tutorials about
ESPN2 uh the toolkit which actually will
have our uh two two two courses and the
the you will get directly final Point uh
the uh
uh the whole other each of the tutorial
and it's gonna be total 10. so by uh
20.7 uh it goes to 30 okay
however this is not a binary okay
sometimes quizzes are you know other two
or three equations
and then you know that we may actually
making some Spirit and the the point can
be actually uh
but this is all all our points by the
way you know I say that this is one
point this is two points but the
internally it's had you know a lot of
kind of uh the sub Target
and you guys will get the half point or
uh the accurate Point uh depending on
your performance
today
I will I made a
uh already made a short quiz
and I would like you to actually uh the
figure out it uh
wait a moment
I think I didn't prepare it okay
I would like you to actually do it right
now
by the way today again you know uh today
is the first cross and some of them you
know may not really kind of our uh the
login to the theater and so on so today
I have an exception that I will extend
this uh the
uh quiz are deadline
uh the to the other end of the day uh
and the quiz is actually not the quiz
this is very uh related to you know uh
what I mentioned for your uh the uh for
our kind of initial product uh please
put your availability of uh in this kind
of when to meet link
and then uh after you finish it you push
it down and submit it
then I will go on
to the rest of the world
uh 4 45 440 to start and the CW Phoenix
in sixth right yeah
okay next the assignments
so assignments uh we have a
two types of assignments
one is the uh are you recorded weekly
assignment
every Wednesday
I will release the assignment
and then we'll ask you to finish it in a
week
and at that time is the uh the Wednesday
right before the poster
okay it's exactly one week
and this is another assignments is the
molecular how to say uh the shuttle
assignment that I say
so it's sometimes you guys may take uh
time but I am
designing it to be finished in uh one
hour working
of course it depends on the person you
know sometimes it may take the your time
uh the you know it's uh that you guys
may think that this is a good trailing
of what it would be
and this this one may also include some
coding and so on but again it is not a
very difficult one
the second one I will call it a coding
assignment
we will have a whole uh the coding
assignment and
we fixed this day but the main change
depending on the kind of a situation in
this case I will kind of announce it
but anyway uh Chris uh the the check
your schedule uh and also consider this
one this one usually I did a uh assign
uh uh two weeks or more than two weeks
longer than two weeks
and they are the kids
got from the future abstraction
hidden Markov model which I will explain
it later in the ground language model
end to end Sr and so on
and these two assignments basically this
is an individual assignments
so you guys can just try to do it by
yourself okay not to you know copy other
people
especially coding assignment 2 is hard I
just don't let you know that in other
words
by the way
after this coding assignment is done and
in general the my class is finished
you guys can actually make a speech
recognition
foreign
duration
so totally assignment is totally sorry
for me
and the other this uh the coding
assignment is Five Point times four
coding assignment it it is four type one
and the weekly assignment that I am
pretty premium uh
and probably uh the the preparer 708
less than 10.
and then of course if it is shorter I
will normalize or adjust it to the other
10.
uh
well anyway that it sounds like you know
this weekly assignment only one point
sounds like a little bit smaller right
however uh this uh weekly assignment is
mostly used for the our midterm uh the
exam
so either working on this other weekly
assignment is a good way to get a better
performance in the midterm exam
and all assignments are released through
the gray score
so please uh data check it
in the next midterm exam again October
26th
and exactly this time just using the the
course time and having a midterm exam
and as I mentioned it's mostly from
weekly assignments
so if people can understand weekly
assignments uh probably you guys can get
the full point
and I may also put some kind of extra
uh the questions which might not be
covered in the uh the my materials or
weekly assignments but talk about in the
important differences and so on
which you guys can actually get some
bonus
and the duster part uh term project
so uh the I think many people are now
familiar with the other custom projects
but anyway this is not the individual
performance you guys first are the maker
project uh the three to five people
three to five is generally people yeah
probably deleted actually
on the bigger side three to four it's a
kind of usual size
and we have a several checkpoint
October 28th is actually uh the quite
one of the important uh data checkpoint
features are the the finishing the team
forming and also the makeup product
proposal and submitting it to that so
October 28 is is not just you know the
beginning it is just already the the
work I want you guys to be starting
something and then you know making a
team and the other the the the summit
product uh that uh this is uh the the
uh the October 28th and we have our
additional checkpoint
to monitor your progress uh in terms of
the term uh the project and the December
7th
actually the last week of the lecture
and the last the class of this lecture
will be a presentation day
and depending on how many teams I will
try to make yeah make it in the poster
or create sort of presentation
presentation that we will decide
depending on the other how many teams
are the the are there in our team
and then finally uh the other asking you
guys to other submit the paper about it
and let's say for example this first
part
uh Team forming the project product of
deadline would be for you to write the
other uh the paper of the other struct
and the introduction
or may also including some other the
obviousness
the second checkpoint here uh is like
you know on a more kind of Define your
proposed method and the main already
finished at least some Benchmark
comparison of the kind of a kind of the
um
and after this uh finally this
presentation is the other permission
deadline uh you will also have a through
uh the the project of abstract
introduction proposed method
experimental setup experimental result
conclusion uh that is kind of the image
that you guys can uh make for this term
project
and the
I have heard some note about it
when you submit the material
for example the weekly
uh the assignments
or
custom
uh the report and so on
you guys have some kind of opportunity
to submit some documents by yourself
and here I would like you to
be careful about it please do not copy
and paste existing materials done by the
others okay
so equations are tables Figures it's
some cases it's okay you guys to take
you know some of the numbers or figures
or equations from some existing
differences this is okay we should
definitely use it but I try to kind of
reproduce it by yourself okay do not do
the other copy and the paste
and it is basically apply to many of our
assignments if we I see that for example
some of your submission
comes from just you know copy or paying
from some of the existing reporter
now you know either we can easily do it
right pqv may actually uh the the degree
the appointment and so on
and I think it is obvious you know it we
should not do it but since I got a lot
of cream so I will explain about it
first uh this is alone legally alone
I've done educational perspective so
some students claim that no legally eat
it buddy
however uh that we have a lot of ethical
reasons uh the uh and the copyright
reason uh we should try not to use that
uh and also this is good for your
educational uh the uh the perspectives
so uh this is that I would not recommend
that uh or some some cases
I will actually decrease the point if
you guys you know that I use some kind
of a cotton paste by the cotton place of
your own materials is fine okay yeah
yeah I'm talking about you know using
some other people's differences
uh because I mentioned this kind of uh
the the things and some students claim
that no no Cindy is also using a cartoon
paste okay yes I'm using a cartoon paste
of my own materials
this is not the cases right yeah so uh
yeah I actually showed you you know for
example for this director I used the
3000 lines of related to you know write
all the equations from the scratch by
myself
um I you know show you the number of
lines to this student
to convince that you know yes I am using
a cut on the face of my own materials
this is not from the other different
materials
so yes um my kind of difference my kind
of uh the lecture I am very careful
about the copyright by the way so some
of the copyright yeah some of the
picture I often use yes why not but most
of them are copyright could even
and the sum of the again you know
equations uh and the tables and so on I
will try to use uh the retype them as
much as possible but due to the kind of
uh the time this direction I sometimes
use a cotton paste so this is a little
bit kind of the inconsistent but I will
try to do my best so I also would like
you guys to do your best
okay finally I think this is the final
one uh the for the grading part that
running policy
so yeah I have to mention because you
know some people always asking
well basically not
accept
uh the extension
uh but you know some of the materials uh
for example we do not as I mentioned we
do not make a binary decision of your
point
we will try to make a uh the Euro kind
of effort and so on so please do your
best uh if you cannot finish it by the
deadline still submit something that we
will try to kind of our how they say
respect to your efforts
and the uh however assignments
I know that we have our
some issues right you know the the sick
or you know important event that you
have to skip so we will around totally
five days
120 hours
so it's corresponding to the the how to
say uh the Working Day in one week okay
so if you guys want to use this one to
attend a conference uh you guys can use
it
and the ice but I think uh the you know
since due to this kind of situation you
guys may get the copies right
and then did uh use this kind of a
five-day buffer uh and so on
and this is very difficult you guys
already use this kind of five day with
some kind of a reason some private
reasons and I have a the confidence so I
want to go there so that give me five
days extra which is very difficult for
me to make it yeah difficult it means no
by the way I'm Japanese so
it's difficult to say no
so instead I will say yeah it is
difficult which means no
yeah
and this five-day extra is for the
assignments and uh the course are the
participations as I mentioned we also
have a two lecture
uh the extra so we have a 22 lectures
and you guys can even skip two of them
uh we'll get the full points
yes no extension but instead we have a
two-day buffer okay
and the I think since we used a
gladoscope so it is very obvious uh but
anyway
uh if we do not specify the time it
would be the end of the day
trying to be ended up the end of the day
if I don't do not specify uh like for
example Friday in the deadline which
means that really Friday in the not in
the uh the anywhere on us by the way
we can change it sometime right so okay
if in the the now it's EDT and it moves
the standard time and ESP but anyway
easy
and this is also important
um
okay
so maybe uh the I would like to ask
accept some questions or comments or uh
the clarification about this uh grading
about this because this is the most
important part any questions or comments
yes is there a reason
is there reason why the class
participation is still inside there are
mostly because we have a tutorials two
tutorial actually having a 10 points so
other one other than that their class
particulation is actually only one point
so it's quite similar to the others yeah
so it's I say it's very similar to the
others usually you know class
participation point to the 20 or
something like that right but we have a
ten percent extra which is for the uh
the ESPN tutorial so at the duties that
we make it uh looks larger but again two
types of the property one internet
uh the participation and the other side
and all we put it by the way in inside
the course uh maybe it's good to
actually showing this one schedule
so
the or we put in the uh Monday and
Wednesday uh in our course
uh
time
and only sometimes we have our deadline
for the private this is not the cost
event
these are dead Prime
and the Border one is a kind of work
the assignment related
video and the non-board upon is
negative property
and we do not have any kind of extra
uh
a participation a requirement other than
our courses
any other questions
okay
cool very cool and we will definitely
but I usually make a kind of specific to
dimension
I'd like to have more you know whether
we the nobility or the survey for having
a bad uh sorry the game tomorrow uh the
lighting with ID I think it is for maybe
I have one more I will clarify it in the
other question uh the project period but
we will definitely make this kind of
dimensions and we'll try to evaluate all
of Europe Festival uh the first time
process based on this kind of Dimension
yeah sorry that the it but I think it's
already somehow clear right yeah but we
will have more the specific verification
about the Customs project okay but
basically I'll say that you know the the
you know if we with this clear this kind
of our Dimension which means you guys
can even submit a paper to icus for
inter speech and so on
so this is to be a kind of you know if
we make it as a single criteria whether
this paper is simple uh codified to the
other I guess for industry to other
speech paper
but of course this is a little bit
cooler the the measure so we will also
uh that consider it uh other several
Dimensions is that clear
cool
any other questions or comments
yeah
okay
Purity for example uh the uh language
the processing might be a little bit
difficult for us to handle but if you
related to speech like you know oh like
for example spoken QA or something like
that you know I'm interested in a QA but
I want to learn speech this course and I
want to in the custom I want to you know
try open QA uh
this level of the variation
fine
at least you guys use the sound
to some extent
that would be fine yeah yeah depend on
the situation but the generally I will
say yes
okay okay
[Music]
um
probably we could use the uh
however I don't know what really
um we have pop is not very poor in terms
of you know but uh for us to get to that
kind of work uh the derivation and so on
so I am still thinking what is
addressing
yeah sorry I don't have an answer but it
is uh the the reason I again put the
kind of midterm exam here
the qualities
uh we try to give you some more
fundamental part and even include in
some verses and so on and
probably I also want to include that
kind of part in the midterm exam due to
that I put this mid comment down in this
timing
because you know otherwise you know all
of these are the neural network but it's
just you know some cases just a neural
network engineering so
um it may not be uh
easy well
yeah whether you guys have no more by
those functions or not
it's a kind of one of the skill which we
try to avoid so yeah very good question
that that part I am not fully decided
yet so that it's maybe asking you guys
to even write it or other the making
everything other uh the greatest scope
uh that that let me that try to find a
good solution uh
okay
but some of the by the way we could be
homework
I would like to ask you guys access
follow the equations and you know
writing that they take or you know 100
and it's also fine but you know Tia is
not happy about it
so it'll be great if you guys write
something with a later Commerce type but
anyway uh that we had this kind of our
uh the the weekly assignment action yeah
any other questions
okay sounds good
I think some of them include our
discussions I also don't fully remember
I will try to remember some of them
sorry I'm saying too late
it's a very good question by the way
okay so and the uh for the
next uh the
this one is also good to uh the share so
I we also this maker kind of our uh this
uh the roles in another box
so of course I will manage everything
right but the uh uh these tears Road
sometimes be charging over that or
sometimes it's just a contact for
example General Logistics probably
better for me to answer it but other you
guys instead of you know asking me if
it's you know may take you know one or
two days you know if for example that uh
now I am fighting with the emnd emnlp
it's not easy to make time so in this
case I may uh my kind of a response will
be a delayed so uh the general logistic
uh the the even uh the the I ask but
this is just a contact okay so
for the general logistic I will try to
be uh in front as much as possible but
cross participation part uh the Jordan
and the assignments uh also have some
kind of uh the specific role for each ta
which again does not mean that you know
uh that this is the only person that you
know are dealing with this but we just
want to hover uh the contact person for
each law so that you guys can also
easily ask the questions and so on
right
so that we make this kind of work
uh the assignment uh for each ga
and finally uh the 40 time project if we
got to the other kind of line map again
each of the kind of a topic we will
assign either one of ta to your project
so that other you guys can also uh
discuss deal with that uh by uh with ta
okay
and I already showed you
uh this uh the schedule
but since this is important I would like
to mention
so today's course in third academic
right and then we will gradually moving
to the core Android remote
and the I will also put the uh the
coding assignment
schedule okay
however please note that we also have a
weekly
assignment each other we will visit in
January Wednesday so we also have a
small kind of a deadline for Wednesday
and all recording assignments
so that the individually
and they
we will actually try to
explain the latest Technologies are not
as possible
in the beginning
some of you may know already the big
equation actually neural network 102 and
neural network network is depressing our
technology
and the uh but the first part is
actually after we have some kind of
end-to-end ASR explanation we will do a
little bit fundamental science
and so on this is called but as we try
to connect it to the details as
technology
so uh that this fundamental part is
trying to kind of make a balance of the
classical fundamental and the modernism
so that's our kind of uh
and uh
after the photo break we will remove the
pure neural network
so uh and including a lot of kind of
end-to-end uh ASR address over
and the right to the other vectors are
not two weeks or a little bit are the
one topic for a get director and so on
but I hope you guys can enjoy this one
okay uh let me move to the crossing
production then
uh yeah
like usual you know the the the teacher
spend a little bit too long time uh done
you know the teacher expected so
I am expecting to finish this part 15
minutes but already one hour so
well this is an important part so I just
didn't
emphasize it okay so now I move to the
course introduction
um so maybe uh the some of you already
made uh the the know this kind of things
but the first uh I like to ask you guys
uh what kind of research topics are
there in uh the speech areas
so this
uh world mostly focus on the speaker
concern right
and the species is a kind of opposite
problem right
and is there any other speech uh
problems that we are studying we are
working we are uh developing
can you guys say something other speech
application
very cool
again
generates Generations Generations
cool cool but it's a kind of a lineup
program of featuring The Voice converter
or even speak in the mountains
very cool is there any other education
decoding we need to segment it right
so we actually have many many uh the
speech problems
uh and the the uh this uh that we have
to actually uh deal with to understand
everything uh of course uh the in this
talk we mostly focus on speaking
positions but we actually can touch
other area a little bit they are very
related
but just stay speed we actually have a
tons of problems
and the question the uh the for example
CMU the
how much topics
CMU covers of this kind of areas
so the answer is everything
[Laughter]
yeah
um this is probably the only uh the the
CMU that can cover everything
you know any other schools may be very
good at speech synthesis is a speech
condition uh and so on but CMU is the
only school that can cover all the kind
of uh the uh our topics and so on CME
actually has a very long history and
also a lot of talented uh faculties to
deal with this kind of our topic
and let's say you know the speech
recognition is our current Focus right
and discuss a little bit about speech
recognition
so speech recognition
um I will explain a bit more details
about what it is however I believe since
people taking this speech conditions and
not understanding means that somehow you
guys know what is important what is
output right
the input is audio signal and auto
parties are completely different
linguistic information
and these are the the problem in terms
of by the way the the conversion this is
super different but this is the most
fundamental function that people are
doing in our area and we can have a lot
of actually applications like our other
Googles
the product other Alexa's products and
so on
and then data uh let's think about the
3D connection research that CMU
now I have to definitely say that we are
the best schools yeah one of them let's
say you know uh the other we should be
humble
we should be humble definitely one of
the best goals uh in speech recognition
of course there are a lot of very good
schools like Johns Hopkins
Cambridge MIT uh and so on
and data they are also very good but the
compared with this course
uh the CM is the uh quite kind of unique
that not only is PG permission but
covering all the other areas so that is
other quite unique
and compared with other schools we also
one of the oldest
our score in other speech recognition
and what actually involved with many of
the speech other the activities other
main players so we are always a main
player uh in the center uh at the center
of the speech research role uh the
and the let me try to discuss about the
history although probably I'm too young
to you know mention about the history of
CMU speech because it started from 1969
which is even before I was born
before some of your parents are born
he actually launched the speech research
in
1969 around 1969. probably before that
we still have such kind of activities
but this is a kind of a remarkable uh
event uh that you know he made a
speeches speech the AI other Institute
in 1969 again before I was born
uh by the way are the larger ready is
one of the speech collection researcher
and he also got actually the Turing
award
so uh the to get you know the Turing
award in the uh the computer science of
course you know that some of them have
to be very fundamental about them but
one way is doing the speech research and
then you guys have a potentially you
know not the zero probability to get the
Turing award that already you know and
approved it
he actually made a dialogue system yeah
and the other since then actually CMU is
leading uh this kind of activities
and one of the notable uh the cmus uh
the autocom is that establish
the current 3D sets technology
so I will explain uh this kind of block
diagram data in my kind of work uh the
adapter but anyway before that uh people
may have you know some kind of a
different systems or combined in some
systems but it doesn't get the enough
performance or a very complicated or not
reproducible or something like that
by 1980s a CMU researchers actually are
combining various techniques and making
it at one system and the realized a real
speech recognition again before that
speed your question was you know just
kind of across classify three consonants
or that some people may either have been
working on the advanced topic and so on
but CME is a wonderful Institute to
establish this kind of speech equation
technology and surprisingly they also
released the opening Source in early
focusing on the uh the open source
activities
so CME Sphinx uh it's at a very famous
uh the other kind of London monk uh
effort uh of uh the after establish
these kind of tools we also making it
that's an open source
there are a lot of other activities uh
for example
um yeah there's a lot of but the
probably one of them this one is also
very famous
foreign
Network 19
which is one of our faculty the RX level
and Jack Clinton uh but Jeff Minton also
used to be in CMU by the way yeah
and this is actually one of the
variations of convolutional neural
networks CNN
it is for the neural network so this is
actually people call it this is one of
the representatives of the second
breakthrough of the neural network you
know there are fast second and now we
have started breakthrough period right
and then yeah that not only this one
this from CMU we actually have a tons of
tons of the research outcomes but not
only comes from the the faculties
sometimes comes from the Student
Activities okay
uh so and I'm very sorry that I don't
have enough time to explain everything
about it so I skip it but the CMU in
general we have a tons of tons of other
technique that are the uh developed and
contribute to the uh in progress of this
that speech recognition
and actually uh as I mentioned the Deep
learning changes the game
uh deep learning this is before the Deep
learning
and this is after the Deep running
and deep learning actually changed again
uh of speech condition and again same is
significantly uh contribute to this
other breakthrough as well
especially the decent breakthrough it's
not very decent already you know the
ieltics data uh five years or so
uh the older kind of speech equation is
now becomes the N2 and the neural
network
and again I will explain a bit more
about what is end-to-end neural network
based feature condition and what is the
kind of the current classical speed
definition
but I just want to mention that the CME
really did uh this uh breakthrough part
as well
uh the uh including the CTC isn't
ctcwsd Edition
but then the spill uh which is also done
by a one of the PhD students here in CMU
hybrid CTC attention listed uh this is
actually my work
[Music]
but but this is actually the
collaboration with uh one of the CMU
students
and the uh our team actually is also
maintaining the espnet which is one of
the defects standard end-to-end speech
equation toolkit
and the dark course try to make the
balance of this kind of end-to-end
neural network and the classical neural
network
so that everyone can understand the
cover this kind of problem and so on
Andy not only this kind of research
contributions
uh I know a lot of CME alumni are
actually working on the
other companies
and actually these the researchers are
not one of them you know uh the holy
people Google has a 300 the the speech
researchers uh the the CMU alumni is
actually in the very important uh senior
director or director level position
uh or uh Apple IBM yeah any other kind
of uh companies working on the big
Industries working on the the speech
processing
uh CME alumni actually are being
important roles
so that I just want to say that the uh
be proud of studying speech at CMU you
guys can be you know the one of them
here or one of them here to make a
breakthrough so I'm very excited to uh
uh work with you guys through this uh
the the course
through this course
so that's the my kind of a course
introduction part and I actually have
some set of introduction but but we only
have nine minutes
do you guys want to
know my answer that just may not say uh
no right so just you know the still have
a nine minutes so four or five minutes
to introduce by myself I think this is
important because you know uh I don't
know uh that uh if you guys you know get
the lecture from some you know teacher
and if you guys know that teachers
background you guys can understand more
about our program and so right so I
think that this kind of introduction is
super important so I usually try to put
it
um
okay so one of the background I wanted
to mention is that the other
I am from the opposite uh the side of
the Earth yeah
and they got the PhD from uh University
which is famous in Japan but not famous
here
maybe I'm very curious how many people
have heard Washington University
oh cool cool actually that I know that
it's famous in China so some of the
Chinese students may know that
Andy I actually spent a very long time
in Japan and working in the industry and
TT which is kind of a uh that something
similar to ATM T yeah
and then I moved to the uh us
and still working at the company
Mitsubishi director degrees
and the uh moving to the John Hopkins in
Baltimore
and then from 2021 I started to work up
here
actually I'm a little bit new since 2021
right yeah a little bit new
still one year and uh one semester
and the
okay so super short bio
so
I'm interested in the speech recognition
machine learning acoustic modeling
adaptation language modeling
yes
and the
actually I am uh the known that I will I
have a very hard to say a good
productivity
so
I already have over 300.
uh the uh
confidence proceedings and the papers
probably from my generation it's quite
uh productive side
and the recently our apps usually hover
around 50 Publications per year
and for example I guess
that's this year I guess we have a 18.
uh the papers and if it is the second
biggest
uh in terms of the single group entry
and the inter-speech
I think we have 20 20
people again from only our single
laboratory entry
I hope it will be the the one of the
biggest but we'll see later if we get
the proceedings we could get that
and I will skip some of my materials
okay so maybe I can uh the uh talk about
uh
uh speech recognition
so actually uh the Now speech
recognition is very cool and that's why
I guess everyone wants to learn right
um this actually causes growing uh many
people actually want to take this
but uh when I started speak your pension
research it's not like that
at that time we don't have any
application
and no breakthrough Technologies
for example when I went to the
conference uh 0.1 or 0.3 percent
Improvement people are very kind of
excited about it
or something like that oh this is a very
cool technology
no no we have a breakthrough a lot of
breakthroughs so we often have a more
kind of the big Improvement
and no impact
and everyone outside the speeches are
actually criticize us
because you know you guys are working on
the uh the the technologies that are not
useful so I yeah a lot of people say
criticize us
and the other more importantly uh
generally the people don't know what is
speech recognition so I have to spend a
lot of time to you know what is speech
recognition the automatically speech
equation to the other people in general
uh like for example my wife my wife is
fine working in a finance and she
doesn't she is not the engineering
person it's take took a quite a long
time for me to understand what is speech
you question now it's easy we can just
you know show the Google home this is
video equation right yeah
so yeah this is actually the the the uh
quite important part now we have our
application very cool
now we have a deep neural network which
actually making uh continue to make a
breakthrough uh deep in your network is
uh the still uh growing our technology
and we have a lot of uh the big impact
due to that
and many people are the outside speech
these are also know
uh this kind of technology and the Very
other respected
and then last one uh what is speech
equation now even my kids know that so I
don't have to explain about it you know
I'm working on inside Google home that's
it
and the okay three more minutes
two more minutes
what is my kind of expert as I mentioned
the speech recognition and other speech
areas are very tightly connected
and one of my kind of expertise of
course peer speed equation algorithm yes
but I
um more it used to be more kind of a
focus on the distant talk speech
recognition and the making of for
example challenge or making a new
technologies and so on now that is what
I was working on it and this distant
speech equation is quite important
technology uh because if it is working
you know used to be we only using this
one as a speech position now the Google
home
like this but still single speaker
but what we are now also working on is
try to understand all the kind of
multi-speaker conversations
and this kind of a technology is also
possible now uh based on a lot of
technology and this is what I am doing
at one of my research topic I have a lot
of research topic but this is one of the
research topics
and we also are the the maintaining uh
the end-to-end speech processing toolkit
called espnet which the hover a lot of
functions are the speech equation takes
big speech translation speech
enhancement and so on
so if you guys are interested in some
kind of other speech uh the the custom
project uh the probably what you can do
mostly done by using our toolkit and so
on
and actually we are doing that
okay this is the kind of uh
including the self-introduction of my
kind of uh the part and the old
coursework
and the final uh take-home message is
that from this the today to you know
entire this semester uh let's enjoy uh
Speech Technologies I try to kind of uh
deliver exciting things uh to you guys
so that's uh the my kind of uh the final
comment thank you so much and see you
soon see you bye